uscellular.com 2019-10-30

# Privacy Information | U.S. Cellular

United States Cellular Corporation ("U.S. Cellular", "we", "us" or "our") is dedicated to earning your trust by protecting your personal information. This Privacy Statement is designed to simply and transparently inform you about the information we collect, how we use it and with whom we share it.

We encourage you to read our Privacy Statement carefully. It explains:

  * What information we collect and from whom.
  * How we collect information.
  * How we use collected information.
  * How we share collected information.
  * How we protect collected information.

### SCOPE

This Privacy Statement explains our practices about collecting, using and sharing personal information. It applies to U.S. Cellular and any Affiliate with whom we share and collect information. "Affiliate" refers to any of the Telephone and Data Systems, Inc. owned family of companies. The Privacy Statement also applies to "Third Parties" whom we require to maintain appropriate privacy and data security measures consistent with this Privacy Statement when we share your information as described in this Privacy Statement. We use "Third Parties" to refer to agents, vendors, suppliers, subcontractors, and independent contractors with whom we have a business relationship.

You authorize U.S. Cellular to collect your information when you interact with us. By subscribing to, accessing or using our products, services, applications and websites ("Services"), you agree to our collection, use and sharing of your information as described in this Privacy Statement. Our Services include wireless services that provide voice, text, and picture messaging; internet access services; data services, such as vehicle and security monitoring; fixed wireless services; websites; and mobile applications.

Some products and services which are branded U.S. Cellular or co-branded with a Third Party may have a stand-alone privacy statement. When a different privacy statement applies, U.S. Cellular will provide you an opportunity to review the applicable terms of service and privacy statement.

When you purchase or use products or services not provided by U.S. Cellular, you are subject to the privacy statement provided by the third party supplier. For example, while using your U.S. Cellular device, you may:

  * Access a Wi-Fi network not provided by U.S. Cellular.
  * Download, purchase or use applications not provided by U.S. Cellular.
  * Post on social media.
  * Purchase from an online retailer.
  * U.S. Cellular is not responsible for the data practices of those third parties.

### CHANGES TO THE PRIVACY STATEMENT

U.S. Cellular may update our Privacy Statement at any time to reflect new legal requirements, changes within our business, or to clarify our practices. Please periodically refer back to the Privacy Statement to learn what changes, if any, have been made based on the effective date posted with the updated Privacy Statement. If we propose to use your information materially different than what was stated in the Privacy Statement at the time we collected it, U.S. Cellular will obtain your consent in the appropriate manner, which may include an opt-out mechanism.

Effective on: **October 1, 2018**.

Updates include: our use of aggregate data for risk modeling; clarifications on the definition of CPNI; and how to exercise your rights to opt-out of certain data sharing.

### TYPES OF INFORMATION WE COLLECT ABOUT YOU

_Personal Information_. Personal Information is any information that identifies and is associated with you directly, or can reasonably be used to identify you. Personal Information may include name, physical and email addresses, telephone numbers, date of birth, Social Security Numbers, Driver's License Numbers, credit card or financial account information, voice recordings or Customer Proprietary Network Information ("CPNI"). Personal Information does not include anonymous or de-identified information that cannot personally identify you, your account or device.

_Customer Proprietary Network Information_. CPNI is a special type of Personal Information that relates to and includes information that we have about you because of the wireless services we provide to you. Please refer to our section on CPNI.

_Network and Device Information_. Network and device information is collected when you use our Services. Certain information such as Advertising IDs and persistent device identifiers indirectly may identify you or your device. Device identifiers include Electronic Serial Numbers (ESN) and mobile equipment identifiers (MEID) which are static numbers linked to a device. Advertising IDs are randomly generated codes on a mobile device that may be changed by the user. This type of information may help identify the same user across multiple devices or channels. Network and device information also may include call records, websites and URLs visited, advertisements clicked, WiFi usage, roaming, browsing history, IP addresses, and device data (battery life, application use, operating system, software configurations). We may collect cookies, web beacons and similar technology. Please refer to our Cookie Policy.

_Location Information_. Location Information is collected when you provide it directly to us and when you use our Services. Location Information may include your physical address, zip code, and a physical address associated with an IP address. Mobile device location may be the location of the tower with associated sector and azimuth that the device is connected to, or the latitude and longitude of a mobile device within a given radius. Certain products or services may also collect precise geolocation information in order to provide you with real time location based services.

### Collection of Information about Children

Our products, services and websites are for general audiences and are not designed to be used by children. We do not knowingly collect, use or share information from children under the age of (13) thirteen. If you allow a child to use our products or services, any information we collect associated with their usage will be treated as your account information in accordance with this Privacy Statement.

### INFORMATION YOU PROVIDE TO US

You provide Personal Information to U.S Cellular when you directly interact with us. When you come into a store, call us, access our website or web chat, participate in a sponsored program, or take a survey; you may provide your contact information such as name, mailing address, telephone number or email address. We also may collect the reasons for your contact, answers to surveys, voice recordings, and recordings collected in stores. When you apply to purchase or register for Services, we may collect your date of birth, Social Security Number, Driver's License Number, credit card information, and authentication information such as PIN number or security questions and answers. And, when you apply for a position with U.S. Cellular, you may provide employment or education history, as well as, in some instances, authorize the collection of consumer report or background check information as part of the application process.

### INFORMATION WE COLLECT AUTOMATICALLY

When you use or access our Services, we collect information about you when you are using our Services. This information may include data about your device and network, such as your mobile number, Advertising IDs, and equipment serial numbers; operating systems, device settings, software configuration and make and model of the device; applications installed on the device; signal strength; IP address and connection speeds. We may collect information about your activity and use of Services such as calls, texts and picture messages sent and received with associated mobile numbers; date, time and call duration; what websites, applications and services were accessed; browsing history including clickstream data, as well as referral URLs and pages visited; search terms; and information when you register for one of our sponsored events.

### Cookie Policy

U.S. Cellular uses cookies, web beacons, pixels, and other tracking technology (collectively "Tag Technology") to deliver, monitor and improve our websites, applications or emails and display relevant content. This Cookie Policy describes the information we collect through Tag Technology, how we use it and how you can manage them. The Cookie Policy applies to U.S. Cellular websites, emails, and applications (collectively "Online Services"). By continuing to access or use our Online Services, you agree to our use of Tag Technology. U.S. Cellular uses Tag Technology on our Online Services and any device interacting with those Online Services will receive it. U.S. Cellular also works with Third Parties to place U.S. Cellular advertisements on their websites and place Tag Technology in your browser when you visit their websites.

A **cookie** is a small text file sent to and stored on your computer or other internet connected device to identify your browser or store information. A first party cookie is set up by the website being visited by the user. A third party cookie is set up by a domain that is not the entity hosting the website. Cookies are widely used to make websites work, work in a more efficient way, and identify and track users. **Web beacons** are small graphic images on a web page or an HTML email that works with cookies to monitor web usage, link web pages to servers, interact with emails, and personalize advertising.

U.S. Cellular may use Tag Technology in order to identify you; provide relevant, interest-based advertising; remember your preferences; secure your access; know when content has been shown to you; provide aggregated auditing, research, and reporting for advertisers; understand and improve our Online Services; and detect and defend against fraud and other risks. When we send you an email, we may use Tag Technology to understand if you have accessed the information provided in the email. We may combine information collected through the Tag Technology with your Personal Information in order to provide you a personalized experience including advertising about products and services you may find of interest. The information we collect from Tag Technology also may allow us to identify you across devices, such as smartphones, tablets, computers or related browsers.

U.S. Cellular may allow Third Parties to place their Tag Technology on our websites or within our advertisements. And, your web browser may request advertisements directly from third party advertising network servers which do not have a business relationship with us. These advertisements may place Tag Technology that can view, edit, or set third party Tag Technology, just as if you had requested a web page from the third party site. U.S. Cellular is not responsible for the practices including the use of Tag Technology, employed by third party websites, mobile applications or online services linked to or from U.S. Cellular Services, or for the content contained therein. You may disable U.S. Cellular and third party Tag Technology on your computer and mobile devices; however, it may limit your experience, including finding pricing and availability of products and services in your area.

Third party websites, mobile applications, and online services you are able to access on the Internet are outside the control or limits of this Privacy Statement.

**Do Not Track**. Depending upon your device, you may be able to set your browser to allow you to control cookies on the device. If you do not want to receive cookies, you may adjust your browser's settings to reject or delete cookies. Deleting or rejecting cookies may impact your ability to effectively interact with our Online Services, third party websites or advertisements or otherwise limit your experience, including your ability to find pricing and availability of products and services in your area. Please consult your browser settings or contact the browser provider to manage your cookies. Our sites and services do not respond to browser's default Do Not Track signals.

### INFORMATION COLLECTED FROM OTHERS

We acquire information about you from credit agencies, financial institutions and other third parties sources, including third party data brokers. These entities may collect information from varying sources such as public records, loyalty cards and social media. The information we collect may include credit reports, consumer reports, criminal records, military records and references, and have information such as gender, age, education level, occupation, marital status, children in household, home value, and categories of interest like reading, music, or sports.

We use the information we collect to provide you Services. We may use it to determine your eligibility for Services; verify your identity; establish and maintain your account; request credit reports and measure your credit worthiness and payment risk; and properly bill and collect for Services. We may use it to route your calls and messages; enforce our Terms and Conditions; respond to account or Service related issues; research and develop new services; and measure the effectiveness of and improve our Services.

We use collected information to protect our network from fraudulent, abusive or unlawful practices, authenticate individuals, and monitor sales transactions for potential fraud. We may access or disclose your information to respond to legal investigations, protect and defend our legal rights and property, protect the safety and security of customers or members of the public including during emergency circumstances, and comply with the law or legal processes such as court orders and subpoenas.

We also may use your information to personalize promotions offered to you; market new products and services to you based on your interests; tailor content you see in advertisements; and conduct industry or consumer surveys. We may use your location to route calls and data services; provide emergency services; identify and authenticate you for purchases or access to the network; and deliver advertising or similar content. To see more about our online advertising practices, please click here. We may also use your mobile device location to provide location-based services.

_Aggregate and De-Identified Information_.Aggregated and de-identified information has been changed in a manner that prevents others from identifying you. We may use aggregated or de-identified information to manage, protect and improve our network and Services; develop network work plans; conduct traffic flow analyses; investigate service issues; develop credit and fraud risk models; and research new products and services. We also may develop analytical tools and methods to measure the effectiveness of marketing and advertising campaigns; develop promotions and offers; and analyze customers' usage patterns. We also may measure the performance of our Services within a specific geographic area.

We will not disclose your information outside of U.S. Cellular, its Affiliates, or Third Parties other than as described in this Privacy Statement unless we have your express or implied consent.

_For U.S. Cellular's Purposes_. We may share your information without your consent with Affiliates and Third Parties that perform activities on our behalf, such as billing and collecting for our Services; assisting in operating our network; managing our platforms and websites; fulfilling and distributing orders; and promoting and marketing our Services. Third Parties that receive information are prohibited from using the information for any purpose other than those for which they are permitted by law or they have contractually agreed to, and if they are processing your information, they have agreed to appropriate privacy and security provisions for the type of information shared.

We also may share certain information for purposes permitted by law without your consent such as to prevent fraud; comply with legal requirements; provide emergency assistance; enforce our Terms of Service and agreements; protect our rights and property, and in the event of the sale of part or all assets or other corporate reorganization.

_Authorized Contacts_. We may share certain account information with individuals whom account owners have authorized to act on their behalf regarding the account ("Authorized Contacts"). We share certain account information with Authorized Contacts and allow them to make inquiries and certain changes to the account. Authorized Contacts cannot change the Personal Information of account owners. Account owners may change Authorized Contacts at any time.

_Roaming Networks_. If you are roaming domestically or internationally on the network of another carrier or WiFi service provider, your wireless telephone number, your location, and the numbers you dial and other information about your usage will be collected, stored and shared by the carrier providing the services. If you are roaming domestically, the privacy policy of the carrier providing your roaming services will apply. If you are roaming internationally, the collection and use of your roaming information may be subject to the regulation and privacy policy applicable in the country in which the carrier is providing services which may be different than the privacy regulations within the United States.

_Aggregate or De-Identified Information_. We may share with Third Parties information that has been collected about you that has been de-identified or aggregated in a manner that prevents others from identifying you. The de-identified or aggregate information may be used for marketing or other analytic purposes, such as to monitor subscriber network interactions, signal strength, dropped calls, or other customer experiences to evaluate customer experience and identify ways to better manage and improve our services, and help make advertising more relevant to you. Once your information has been de-identified or aggregated, U.S. Cellular does not attempt to re-identify the information. We also prohibit Third Parties from attempting to re-identify the information or allowing downstream users to re-identify the information.

_Advertising_. As mentioned in the Cookie Policy above, U.S. Cellular may allow Third Parties to place Tag Technology on your device when you access our websites, applications or advertisements and collect the preferences you demonstrate when interacting with them. These Third Parties may use the collected information to personalize advertising that may be of interest to you when you are on other websites or applications. U.S. Cellular adheres to the Digital Advertising Alliance's Self-Regulatory Principles for Online Behavioral Advertising ("DAA's Self-Regulatory Principles for OBA") and only uses third party advertisers that pledge their adherence to these principles. To find out more about online behavioral advertising or learn to opt-out of the collection and use of your information click here.

Your web browser may request advertisements directly from third party advertising network servers which do not have a business relationship with us. These advertisements may place Tag Technology that can view, edit, or set third party cookies, web beacons and tag technology, just as if you had requested a web page from the third party site. U.S. Cellular is not responsible for the practices including the use of Tag Technology, employed by third party websites, mobile applications or online services linked to or from U.S. Cellular Services or for the content contained therein.

_Third Party Applications You Install On Your Device_. We have no authority over third party applications you may install or access on your device. By installing or accessing these applications, you may consent to allowing third parties access to information on your device including your Network and Device Information in order to support the application's functionality. The Network and Device Information shared may include Advertising IDs or device identifiers in order to provide more personalized experiences, including for marketing purposes such as delivering interest-based advertising. Third party websites, mobile applications, and online services you are able to access on the Internet are outside the control or limits of this Privacy Statement.

_Directory Information_. U.S. Cellular does not publish or support directories of our customers' wireless phone numbers nor do we make this information available, without your consent, for listing in public directories.

### Wireless Location Information

U.S. Cellular's network receives and tracks location information so that it may route communications, deliver wireless content and properly bill customers for its Services. We may use your location information when you use our mobile applications and Online Services to provide location-based services ("LBS"), which are services that rely upon real-time physical, geographical location information provided by a device to provide a service to the customer. LBS may include roadside assistance services, fleet management services, or mapping services with turn-by-turn directions.

We may also disclose location information to other parties with your consent, or as required by applicable law including but not limited to public safety, fire service or law enforcement officials in emergency situations. We may share location information with your consent to other parties which provide advertising, as well entities that provide LBS and or mobile applications that track the location of the mobile device using our network with or without our assistance. Once you provide your consent to transfer a mobile device's location information from U.S. Cellular to the party that provides the LBS or mobile application, that party's privacy policy will govern the use of that location information. You should understand the risks involved in consenting to the disclosure of a mobile device's location information before requesting a LBS or mobile application that collects and uses your location information.

U.S. Cellular retains location information only so long as needed to provide and support location-based services or mobile applications, as required by law, or as necessary for valid business purposes.

U.S. Cellular does not guarantee the accuracy or completeness of location information delivered through its network, and any location-based service or mobile application may be disrupted or fail due to environmental factors and factors affecting satellite usage. U.S. Cellular abides by the International Association for the Wireless Telecommunications Industry ("CTIA") Best Practices and Guidelines for Location Based Services which can be found at the CTIA's website at [http://www.ctia.org](http://www.ctia.org/).

Customer Proprietary Network Information ("CPNI") is created by virtue of our relationship with you as your telecommunications service provider. CPNI includes your type and quantity of certain telecommunications services you subscribe to and includes details about your calling, text messages and picture messages. Call detail information includes the date, time, call-to location, number called or the number the call was received from, and minutes and charges of the call. Text or picture messaging detail includes the date, time, and number the message was sent to or received from, but does not include message content. CPNI does not include your name, address, and phone number, or other data generated by information services such as internet access services or data services like vehicle or security monitoring. Use of CPNI is subject to federal laws and regulations.

We may use CPNI to provision your services; generate, bill and collect for your service; respond to your requests; enforce our Terms of Service; and protect against fraudulent use of the network. We may also use CPNI to recommend other wireless products and services. U.S Cellular also may share your CPNI with its Affiliates and Third Parties to market U.S. Cellular Services on our behalf. The CPNI rules permit our use of this information for these purposes provided we safeguard it from unauthorized disclosure. We employ reasonable security measures and processes to help ensure your CPNI is protect from unauthorized use or disclosure.

U.S. Cellular is prohibited under the CPNI rules from allowing our Affiliates and agents to use this information without your consent for marketing Affiliates' and agents' communications-related services to you. Your consent allows them to use CPNI to suggest their communications-related services to you or assist you with other telecommunications needs. Affiliates and agents have the same duties to safeguard your CPNI as we do.

When you become a customer of U.S. Cellular and no later than every two years thereafter, a notice will be provided to you explaining your rights about CPNI ("CPNI Notice"). You can expect to receive your CPNI Notice on your bill each month, in a separate mailing, or in a text message with a link to the CPNI Notice if you have prepaid wireless services. You must contact us as described in Managing Your Preferences below and in the CPNI Notice if you do not want to grant consent to our Affiliates or agents to use your CPNI to market their communications-related services to you. We will assume you have provided consent if you do not contact us beginning 30 days after the first time we provide you notice in your bill or in a text message.

### Accessing Your Information

U.S. Cellular takes reasonable measures to assure you that the information we collect, use and share is accurate, complete and current. We make good faith efforts to provide you with access to your information to allow you to correct it if it is inaccurate or to delete it at your request unless the law or legitimate business reasons require us to keep it. Account owners and Authorized Contacts who wish to review or change their Personal Information may do so by contacting us at the number provided on their billing statement, visiting a retail store, accessing their information online through My Account, or by contacting us via e-mail.

Account owners and their Authorized Contacts are required to have their own PIN and security questions/answers for account protection. When account owners or their Authorized Contacts contact us via phone, they may be asked to provide their PIN or answer security questions so we may authenticate them before responding to their questions or changing to their Personal Information. Account owners and their Authorized Contacts may be asked to present a valid government issued photo ID in retail stores for authentication purposes before we respond to their questions or change their Personal Information. Account owners and Authorized Contacts should not provide account information, their PIN or online password to unauthorized parties.

We are not required to process requests for information that are unreasonably repetitive or systematic, require disproportionate technical effort, jeopardize the privacy of others, or may be extremely impractical (for instance, requests concerning information residing on backup tapes), or for which access is not otherwise required. In cases in which we provide information access and correction, we perform this service free of charge, except if doing so would require a disproportionate effort.

### California Privacy Rights

A business subject to California Code § 1798.83 is required to disclose to its customers, upon customer request, the identity of any other party to whom the business has disclosed "personal information" regarding that customer within the immediately preceding calendar year. A business is only required to respond to a customer request once during the course of a calendar year.

If you are a California resident and would like to make such a request, please submit your request in writing to:

U.S. Cellular   
Attn: Director, Privacy and Senior Counsel   
8410 W. Bryn Mawr Ave.   
Chicago, IL 60631-3486   
Fax: 773-864-3133

### Protecting Your Information

U.S. Cellular takes reasonable security safeguards to protect against such risks as loss or unauthorized access, destruction, use, modification, or disclosure of information. U.S. Cellular uses a variety of commercially reasonable and appropriate safeguards to protect information residing on its systems from unauthorized access or disclosure including, without limitation, server firewalls and physical facility security.

We restrict access to information to those who need to know that information in order to operate, develop or improve our products and services. These individuals are bound by confidentiality obligations and may be subject to discipline, including termination and criminal prosecution, if they fail to meet these obligations. We also have appropriate practices and procedures designed to protect your information. We train our employees on the proper handling and securing of information which includes reporting potential privacy concerns. We protect the security of your information transmitted through our websites by using software which encrypts certain Personal Information you input or view.

We will not store Confidential Personal Information beyond what is necessary for business purposes, including for internal service evaluation and quality assurance purposes, except as otherwise required by law.

We cannot prevent every unauthorized attempt to access information. If you suspect an issue with access to your information, please contact a customer service associate by calling 1-888-944-9400.

### Controlling Unsolicited Text Messages and E-mail ("Spam")

U.S. Cellular is concerned about controlling unsolicited commercial text messages and e-mail or "spam." Although U.S. Cellular continues to actively review and implement new technology to help prevent these activities, there is no currently available technology that will permit U.S. Cellular to totally prevent the sending and receiving of unsolicited text messages or e-mail. Using junk e-mail tools and being cautious about the sharing of your e-mail address while online may help reduce the amount of unsolicited e-mail you receive. For more information about this and other related topics go to the Federal Trade Commission's website at [http://www.onguardonline.gov](http://www.onguardonline.gov/).

Customers may access their information through their monthly bill or My Account. To correct or update your information:

  * Contact a customer service associate by calling 1-888-944-9400.
  * Speak with an associate in a store.
  * Current customers may: 
    * Dial *611 from their U.S. Cellular handset.
    * Access My Account.

When visiting our website, you may leverage your web browser to manage or restrict our Tag Technology.

  * <https://youradchoices.com/control>

To learn how to opt-out of the collection and use of your information for online behavioral advertising:

  * <https://youradchoices.com/control>

You may opt-out of sharing your CPNI with our affiliates for marketing purposes by:

  * Calling our toll-free CPNI Opt-out Line: 1-800-509-6254; please follow the recorded instructions.
  * TTY users can opt-out by first dialing a telecommunications relay service (TRS) center, via 711, in order to contact a TRS Communications Assistant (CA). Ask the CA to dial 1-800-509-6254 and follow the recorded instructions.

Questions and comments may also be directed to us at:

U.S. Cellular   
Attn: Director, Privacy and Senior Counsel   
8410 W. Bryn Mawr Ave.   
Chicago, IL 60631-3486   
Fax: 773-864-3133
